Hello everyone and welcome to English POD.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and today we're talking
about American
education and college life.
That's right, this is
actually a user suggestion
that they wanted to
know more or less what
it would be like a dialogue between
friends on a typical day in college.
Alright, so this is an advance of a lesson.
We're going to be talking in
a normal conversational speed.
We're going to listen
to the dialogue and when
we come back we'll
talk about some of these
Q phrases and words that might help
you understand the dialogue better.
Hey Jordan, is that you? Long time no see.
Oh hey no kidding. I haven't seen
you since orientation three months ago.
So how you been?
Settling in a college life okay?
Yeah I think so.
I play just fine.
I owe it to Alpha. So I'm
living at the frat house now.
Oh so you're a frat boy now huh?
Yeah yeah I know it's totally cliche but
really I think it's been a good decision.
Got a lot of support and good
suggestions from the guys.
What about you what have you been up to?
Well not much. I'm still living at
home and commuting to school.
I ended up dropping that metal
working class I was so excited about.
It just wasn't as interesting as I'd hoped.
The guidance counselor
suggested that I focus on my
prerequisite courses so that I
can make sure the credits count.
That sounds smart but kind of boring.
Yeah it is a little bit.
I joined the great outdoors club
though which has been a lot of fun.
We've gone on two camping trips
already and I've made some good friends.
That's cool.
Hey so have you decided on your major yet?
Definitely pre-med. What about you?
I still have no clue but we don't have to
declare a major till our sophomore year.
So I've got time.
Oops I'm late for class. Got her on.
Okay take care.
Hey nice running into you. Yeah you too.
Alright we're back so
now let's start with all
these words and phrases
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So hey Jordan is that you long time no see.
I love this phrase.
Right this phrase long
time no see which if
you look at it it doesn't
really make sense.
It looks like we're missing a couple words.
It looks like an incomplete sentence.
Yeah like the subject.
Right.
I haven't seen you. You haven't seen you.
So really the meaning of this is I
haven't seen you in a long time.
That's right and actually I've heard
that this phrase was taken from Chinese.
I've also heard that so it's
kind of like pigeon English
and now it's very very
common in English to say this.
You say this with your friends.
It's very casual and yeah long time no see.
Because if you translate this literally
to Chinese it makes sense right.
So it's interesting.
Alright so we haven't seen our
friend in a long time and he's like
yeah no kidding you know what
I think it's been since orientation.
So what is this orientation
that he's talking about?
Now this is an important part of the
average American college experience.
Orientation is a special time
maybe for one week or a couple
days at the very beginning
of your first year of university.
Alright so my first week of school I
didn't have any classes but I went to
school and with all of the other first
year students we're called freshman.
I had to do activities and meet people
and sign up for classes and basically
orientation is a time when you learn
about a new system or a new program.
So how it works because you know maybe you
don't really know yet how to pick your classes
or where the dorms are or how the meals
work if you have to go to the cafeteria etc.
Exactly and it comes
from the verb to orient.
So I orient myself by
facing the right direction.
So orientation is really about teaching
you how to start in a new system.
Okay very good.
So well in that was three
months ago and a lot has
happened our speaker says
that he pledged Phi Iota Alpha.
So what is this to pledge in
this now this is Greek as well.
Phi Iota Alpha is Greek and this means
that we're talking about a fraternity.
So fraternity is a
group of boys a sorority
is a group of girls and
these are communities.
So social societies that you
have to apply to be a member of.
So we don't say apply.
We pledge.
So it's like I pledge allegiance.
You say I want to be in your group.
I want to be in your
fraternity and so you will
have to do special things
to become a member.
So the verb to pledge would be to to
promise something honorably or faithfully.
Exactly.
And that's the nice way of putting it.
But generally when you talk about sororities
and fraternities these upperclassmen.
So third, fourth year
students they make the
students who are pledging
do very weird things.
So as you said this is for these
two guys this is for a fraternity
but if it's this type of club
for girls it's called a sorority.
So it's different.
So I'm pledging this
sorority that means I'm
trying to become a
member of this sorority.
So I think it's worthwhile mentioning many
of you have probably seen it in movies.
These fraternities or sororities and they
all have names based on the Greek alphabet.
So the letters Phi Iota Alpha
or Kappa Kappa Gamma.
These are the letters that are basically
represent the name of the fraternity.
And what's interesting is that maybe I
am in Kappa Kappa Gamma at my school.
There's another school with another
Kappa Kappa Gamma we're all related.
It's the same social community.
So they sometimes do events
together, things like that.
So actually these fraternities or
sororities it's not independent to a school.
It's actually like a wide network
of people that belong to this club.
Exactly.
It's a national network usually.
So it's kind of like
being in the Boy Scouts.
Yeah similar except the
activities are much different.
That's right.
So these people they
may live at the frat house
like in this dialogue he's
living at the frat house.
Now remember here fraternity that
becomes frat if we're talking colloquially.
So the frat house is the fraternity house.
It's where those boys live.
But only the Phi Iota Alpha boys.
Right.
So no one if I have a friend and he's not
Phi Iota Alpha then he can't live there.
Exactly.
And we have a similar thing
for girls that's the sorority house.
Okay very good.
So a frat house is the fraternity
house basically like their club house.
Where they live though yeah.
Right.
So sometimes guys that belong to
fraternities they refer to as frat boys.
Hey frat boy yeah.
So fraternity boy this is not
always the nicest thing to say.
It's got a negative meaning because a lot
of the activities that frat boys do stay
typically involve lots of
drinking and maybe being loud.
So frat boy is someone
who's in a fraternity
and it's usually a critical way
of talking about those guys.
So this whole fraternities sorority
thing as he said is a little bit cliche.
Right.
Yeah this is a great word.
I use this a lot actually
so something that's
cliche would be
almost what's expected.
Right.
But in a bad way.
And so so you joining
a fraternities is a
little bit cliche
because it's kind of like.
It's what everyone does
in the movies and on TV.
Right.
I'm going to college.
I'm going to join a fraternity.
It's almost like boring it's so normal.
Right.
We could also say
that let that movie at
the end of the movie,
the man and the woman,
they fought but then
they got back together.
It's so cliche.
Right.
So it's something that's
overused, expected.
Yeah.
Very typical.
Uninteresting.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we have a cliche.
We're saying that a fraternities cliche.
Now the other guy on the
other hand is living off campus.
He lives at home.
But he said he commutes
to school every day.
So he says I'm commuting to school.
This is interesting.
Now in America there
is usually two options.
One is to live on campus.
That means to live at your university
in a dormitory or an apartment.
But many people commute.
And this means they drive to school every
day and then they drive home at night.
They don't live on the campus.
So you can also commute to work every day.
Right.
This is what people do.
You don't live at the office.
Exactly.
I hope not.
No, this is a common thing.
You don't drive to work and you might
ask them how long is your commute?
Uh huh.
You say, oh, one hour.
That means I drive one hour to work.
So if I take the bus or the train
the subway, is that also commuting?
It is.
It doesn't matter how you do it.
It just means you don't live
where you work or where you study.
So you have to travel there by
some means of transportation.
Okay.
So well, now going back
to the academic aspect of
this dialogue, he said that
he ended up dropping a class.
Okay.
So to drop means to stop attending a class.
Maybe you don't have enough time.
Maybe you don't like it.
But to drop a class means
you will no longer study.
You will not take the tests.
You will not get a grade.
It's the opposite of to sign up
for a class or to register for a class.
So the difference
between dropping a class
and failing a class is
that basically you're
making the decision to
not go there anymore.
Exactly.
And usually there's a time you can do this.
So for the first two weeks,
you can attend classes.
And if you don't have enough time or you
don't like a class, you can drop the class.
But if you stay in the
class, you just don't
come or you do very
poorly on your tests.
That's called failing.
So there are some classes
because I don't know.
Can you drop any class or do you
have to take them at some point?
That's a good question.
It's our next phrase.
That's a prerequisite course.
So usually the university in America
will tell you you have to study math.
You have to study one semester of science.
You have to study English for one semester.
So these are called prerequisites.
It's when the university tells
you you have to study something.
And I think you also have
some courses that you
can't take until you've
passed some other course.
So like for example,
you can't take economy
unless you've passed,
I don't know, calculus.
Exactly.
That's another prerequisite.
So we'd say the prerequisite
for economics is calculus one.
Or the prerequisite for
Spanish 200 is Spanish 100.
It means you have to take something
before you take something else.
So there's two meanings of the word,
but they're both related to requirements.
What you have to do.
Okay.
You need a requirement.
Now, moving on and
talking about the major,
he said, if, well, if you decided on
a major and he said, well, pre-med.
All right.
So major first of all is what
you choose to study, right?
Right.
Focus.
You might study other classes, but your
focus, your main interest area is one thing.
And in his case, he's
talking about pre-med.
Now, what does pre-med stand for?
Because it is a short
version of a longer word.
Right.
So it's pre-medicine.
Yeah.
Okay.
So medicine is something you
study if you want to be a doctor.
Right.
So pre because in America, you don't,
you don't become a doctor after four years.
Right.
You have to go get your
BA, your bachelor's degree.
And then you have to get
your PhD, your doctorate.
So people who want to go to graduate school
first have to study many required courses.
That's the pre-med focus.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
So that's what he's talking about.
He's definitely going to focus on pre-med.
He wants to be a doctor.
He's not going to be a doctor soon, but
he wants to start studying to be a doctor.
So he will, he will become a
pre-med, a pre-med major.
And what about, uh, for lawyers?
I know that there are also
something that you focus on before.
There is.
Yeah, that's called pre-law.
Same idea.
Pre-means before.
Um, so obviously a lawyer needs
to study for a long time as well.
And with your undergrad degree, so your
first four years, you would study pre-law.
So this is what you focus
on for your four years
and then you go into grad school and become
an attorney or a specific type of lawyer.
But a lawyer doesn't
have to study for a PhD.
A lawyer studies for a JD.
That's JD.
Yeah.
Juris doctorate.
That's the law degree.
Uh-huh.
Interesting.
Okay.
So well, he's going into
pre-med, but the other
guy, he's like, well, I
don't have a clue yet.
Uh, and he doesn't have to declare
a major until the sophomore year.
Okay.
A couple of things
going on here, first of
all, there are different
names for each year.
Right.
So freshmen, sophomore,
junior, senior, one, two, three, four.
So sophomore year is the second year.
So if you say I'm a
sophomore student at XY
university, that means
you're in your second year.
Exactly.
And he says that he
doesn't have to declare a
major until his second year,
until his sophomore year.
And this phrase to declare
a major is very important.
It means that you will tell the
university what your focus will be.
Right.
Yes.
You can't just go to
school and then graduate.
You have to say, I will
focus on this because
every major has what
we just talked about.
Prerequisites.
Right.
So, but in this first
year, you don't have to
tell the university yet
what you want to study.
Maybe you just, you
take a variety of courses
and then you tell them, okay, now
I'm going to focus on this, right?
Exactly.
That's what I did.
And that's very common
for liberal art schools.
Maybe if you're in a
specific trade school
or you're in a certain track, you
would have a different situation.
But for me, liberal
arts, I studied history, I
studied philosophy, I studied
language and literature.
And then my sophomore year, my second year,
I decided, oh, I will study philosophy.
And that's-- So you're
going to focus on that?
Yes, one thing.
So it's interesting
because in many other
countries, the education
system requires you
to declare your major before
you start studying, right?
You say, well, I'm going to study business
and then your four years are around that.
Whereas in some places
in the United States
or for some majors,
you don't have to do that.
That's true.
And I've also heard in England, for example,
you have one area of study, one major.
And that's all you study.
Right.
Because in the US, you can get a major in
history with a minor in philosophy, right?
Exactly.
The opposite, I had a major in
philosophy and a minor in history.
So major means something
bigger, more important
and minor is smaller
or less important.
And a minor is your second field of study.
So you take fewer classes, but
you still know something about that.
But do they always have to be related?
Because for example,
can you be a major of
philosophy with a minor in, I don't
know, astronomy or something like that?
Absolutely.
Something like pre-med, so medicine, it's
hard because there's so many requirements.
But I had a number of
friends who are major
in computer science and a
minor in literature, for example.
So you can mix it up at certain schools.
So what would be the advantage
of doing something like that?
Because most places or
most education systems
say that you teach that you should
specialize or should be focused on one area.
So if you're in computer science,
then you should be focused on that.
So why would somebody
specialize in computer science in their
major, but then take a minor
in like literature or something?
Well, let's use that example.
I think one of the
benefits for the liberal
arts degree, and this
is something they talk
about a lot in education, is that
you have a broad area of knowledge.
So yes, you know a lot
about computer science.
You have to to graduate,
but maybe in your
future you will write
articles about computer
science or you want to blog or you want
a job that has a public relations aspect.
You need to know how to write.
And you're not going
to learn how to write
in all of your computer
science classes, but
you will by reading a lot and
writing a lot in your literature classes.
So some people like
to say that it's very good
to mix up business and
languages or computer
science and literature because
it's a way to be well rounded.
That's right.
That's actually interesting because in most
places, specifically in the exact sciences
fields, they focus more
on that, like engineers.
It's all about engineering
math and all this.
But the human aspect,
like you said, or the
liberal arts aspect, like literature or
history, they don't get much of that.
So when you actually
have to become a manager
or write or manage
people that you don't
really have the skills to do that
because you never really took a class.
That's right.
And it can be very
hard to learn how to
write well and to speak
well all of a sudden.
And I think that's where people struggle
also when they're applying for jobs.
So I don't know, I believe in
being a well-rounded individual.
Obviously, there's some benefits to being
very, very knowledgeable about one thing.
So I guess we could ask
you guys, are users, do
you believe that it's
better to be knowledgeable
about one thing or
maybe more well-rounded
and to be an expert in
many different things?
That's right.
Yeah.
You should let us know.
Let's jump into our dialogue one last time.
Let's take a look at what everyone
was saying and we'll be back in a bit.
Hey, Jordan, is that
you a long time, no see?
Oh, hey, no kidding.
I haven't seen you since
orientation three months ago.
So how do you been
settling into college life, okay?
Yeah, I think so.
I played just fine.
I owe it to Alpha, so I'm
living at the frat house now.
Oh, so you're a frat boy now, huh?
Yeah, yeah.
I know.
It's totally cliche.
But really, I think it's
been a good decision.
Got a lot of support and good
suggestions from the guys.
What about you?
What have you been up to?
Well, not much.
I'm still living at home
and commuting to school.
I ended up dropping
that metalworking class.
I was so excited about it.
Just wasn't as interesting as I'd hoped.
The guidance counselor
suggested that I focus
on my prerequisite courses so that
I can make sure the credits count.
That sounds smart, but kind of boring.
Yeah, it is a little bit.
I joined the great outdoors club,
though, which has been a lot of fun.
We've gone on two camping trips
already, and I've made some good friends.
That's cool.
Hey, so have you decided on your major yet?
Definitely pre-med.
What about you?
I still have no clue, but
we don't have to declare
a major till our sophomore
year, so I've got time.
Oops.
I'm late for class.
Got her on.
Okay.
Take care.
Hey, nice running into you.
Yeah, you too.
All right.
So it's a very interesting topic.
Education systems are so
different around the world.
The way that you go to
college, how many years
I know that in England you
can do a master's in a year.
I think one year.
Whereas in the
States, it's two or I think
even a bachelor's in
England is three years.
I believe so.
Yeah, but they also have
an extra year of high school.
An extra year of high school.
Okay.
So every system is a
bit different and America
generally, it's either two or four
years for your college degree.
And then, yeah, it's graduate
school for two, three or four years.
Now, one of the
interesting things and that I
found is kind of unique
to the Latin American
education system is
that people can actually
go to college for five years
for majors like in business.
And what they do is they
call it a commercial engineer.
So it's a engineering, you
know, it's like an engineering
major, but it's not really
engineering because it's business.
So it's interesting because
you go to school for
five years to be come to
get to be a business major.
Interesting.
What we have something
called a joint program,
J-O-I-N-T, joint
meaning coming together.
And you could do that.
You could be, for
example, a chemistry major,
but also business major
and then maybe go
into oil refinery or,
you know, some kind of
very specialized business where you do
need to know something about chemistry.
And that's called a joint degree.
Oh, that's really smart as well.
Yeah.
Well, it's interesting.
Let us know what you studied.
Maybe you went to school for two years.
I think you can get a technical
degree is it in two years?
Associate's degree or a
technical degree for two years.
And then you can get a
bachelor's, a master's, a PhD.
Let us know what your education background
is like and how it works in your country.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right, guys.
Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]